JOHN COLELLA

4 631 838 8222

₱ Brooklyn, NY

in

www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcolella

• https://github.com/jmcolella

Summary

I am a web developer skilled in building apps using Rails, React, JavaScript, Bootstrap and Sinatra. I have a passion for design and love working the full stack to create meaningful projects. With experience working in fastpaced environments, I'm a team player who can work efficiently with others to meet hard deadlines. I have excellent communication and organizational skills along with analytical experience that has proven effective in collaborative environments.

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript(JQuery)

HTML5

CSS3

SQL

FRAMEWORKS

Rails

React

Bootstrap

Materialize

Jekyll

Sinatra

PLATFORMS

Google Maps API

Yelp API

Twitter API

DATABASES

PostgresSQL

ActiveRecord

SQLite

TESTING

RSpec

Jasmine

Capybara

METHODOLOGIES

Object Oriented Design Test Driven Development

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Italian

Employment

SICORE TECH Front End Developer Farmingdale, NY Aug 2016 to Current

- · Oversee and build a browser-based user interface for an embedded securities software.
- Use React framework to organize and construct app for the interface.
- Assist embedded systems engineer with building a custom HTTP server in C.

KATTEN MUCHIN ROSENMAN LLP

Paralegal

New York, NY Jun 2013 to Mar 2016

- · Partner with leadership and associates to secure loans for multi-million dollar real estate investments.
- Manage the organization and transferral of legal documents between attorneys and clients.
- Liaise with internal and external parties to ensure post-closing procedures and deadlines were secured.
- · Analyze legal documentation to facilitate drafting new documents for future projects.
- · Oversee the integration and training of new paralegal hires into the firm.

TRIBECA FILM

New York, NY

Acquisitions/Marketing Intern

- Jan 2015 to Aug 2015
- Generate performance reports for video-on-demand data to understand national market for Tribeca Film titles.
 Compile master revenue report of external independent titles for leadership to determine market size for competitor's titles.
- Analyze marketing practices of major video-on-demand vendors to best strategize promotion of Tribeca titles with these vendors.
- Take lead on portions of marketing outreach by analyzing social media statistics to determine best business partners for particular Tribeca titles.

MAGNOLIA PICTURES

Marketing/Publicity Intern

New York, NY Jan 2013 to May 2013

- Serve as first point-of-contact and main liaison for guests via e-mail, phone and at the Magnolia office front desk.
- Compile press information regarding Magnolia releases for marketing to track performance of Magnolia titles.
- Research business contacts for targeted Magnolia releases and update database with information for future use.
- Set up promotional materials, prepared a theater and ushered guests as part of a Magnolia premiere screening.

Projects

LOCALEYES

http://www.localeyestrips.com

An app that connects tourists to day trips curated by locals. Made in 7 days as a group project.

- Built with Rails 4 and the Materialize front end framework
- Incorporated Google Maps and Places APIs to retrieve information for created day trips
- Used JQuery and AJAX for commenting, favoriting and communicating with Google Places API
- Responsible for styling and organizing inbox and messaging system between users; made use of the Mailboxer gem
- · Assisted with the set up of Facebook OAuth and implementation of Devise security gem

HOPSEARCH

https://hopsearch.herokuapp.com/

A web app that allows users to search for numerous hop varietals and learn more about their attributes

- Built with Ruby on Rails 4 back end and React.js views on the front end. Utilize the Bootstrap 3 CSS framework for styling
- Incorporated the BreweryDB API for hop information as well as the Google Maps API to display a map of major hop
 growing regions
- Completed research to fill in missing gaps in BreweryDB API to create a unique information database for users
- · Fully tested models, controllers and routes with RSpec

256: A 2048 CLONE

https://github.com/jmcolella/2048-clone

A clone of the popular game 2048.

- Built using vanilla JavaScript along with the JQuery and Underscore.js libraries.
- Used object-oriented principles to compose game and determine logic for winning or losing the game.

Education

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK

B.A. Film Studies 2013

Thesis: The tradition of "mono no aware" in the films of Yasujiro Ozu.

DEV BOOTCAMP

2016

19-week intensive program focusing on competencies in Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails.